Interest in data science is at an all time high, and
對數據科學的興趣處於歷史最高點，
really has exploded in popularity in the last couple of years.
在過去幾年中真的爆炸式增長。
A fun way to see this is to hit up the Google Trends website.
一個有趣的方式去看到這一點的是點擊Google趨勢網站(trends.google.com)。
Google Trends shows search keyword information over time.
Google趨勢顯示日積月累搜索關鍵字的資訊。
We could see that the term ‘data science’ is massively popular,
我們可以看到，“數據科學”一詞在全球受到
really all across the globe.
廣泛歡迎。
We can also see that related queries include topics like python.
我們也可以看到有關的查詢包括像python這樣的主題。
And we can even see certain tool kits that we’ll be teaching in this course.
我們甚至可以看到我們將在本課程中教授的某些工具。
For instance, here's the trend for
例如，這是python
python pandas, which is the focus of module two and three in this course.
Pandas的趨勢，這是本課程中第二和第三部分的重點。
Before we jump in to a discussion of data science, I'd like to take a moment and
在我們開始討論數據科學之前，我想花一點時間，
have you reflect on what you think data science is, and
讓你思考你對數據科學的看法，
why you came to this course to explore.
以及為什麼你來探究這個課程。
If someone you ran into asked you what data science was all about,
如果你遇到一個人，問你數據科學是什麼，
what would you tell them?
你會怎麼告訴他們？
The history of data science goes back a little further than 2004,
數據科學的歷史可追溯至2004年之前，
which is where the Google search term history begins.
這是Google搜索歷史記錄開始的時候。
But this, at least, gives a sense for how popular the area is now.
但是，至少覺得現在這個領域受歡迎的程度。
I think the popularity of interest in the area comes from the network and
我認為該領域的普遍受歡迎，來自我們發現自己所處的網路和
data driven society we find ourselves living in.
數據驅動的社會。
When people think of the term data scientist,
當人們想到'數據科學家'一詞時，
they tend to think of Google or Amazon or Facebook,
他們經常想到Google或Amazon或Facebook，
places with big artificial intelligence research teams, and certainly these
這些有大型人工智慧研究團隊的公司，當然這些
are some amazing companies who are doing great things with data science.
都是一些令人驚奇的公司，他們在數據科學方面做得很好。
But data scientist aren’t just limited to careers with tech companies.
但數據科學家不僅僅局限於科技公司的職業生涯。
Almost every company is turning to data science to better understand how to build
幾乎每個公司都在轉向數據科學，以更好地了解如何構建
products, serve customers and leverage new opportunities.
產品，為客戶服務並利用新的機會。
And companies aren't the only one. In this first course I will be giving
公司不是唯一的。在這第一門課程中，我將在
lectures here in the University of Michigan digital innovation greenhouse.
密歇根大學的數字創新大廳舉行講座。
Which was a lab within the office of academic innovation.
這是一個學術創新辦公室的實驗室。
The space is used by a team which includes programmers, behavioral scientists and
這個實驗室由包括程式設計師，行為科學家和
data scientists who aim to build technologies to support next generation
數據科學家在內的團隊使用，他們的目標在構建技術來支持下一代
teaching and learning.
的教學和學習。
The background of individuals here is very broad and
這裡每一個人的背景非常廣泛，
includes folks with computer science and
包括計算機科學和
information degrees, psychology degrees, and law and business degrees.
資訊學位，心理學學位以及法律和商業學位。
And here they apply data driven methodologies to aid in their discovery,
在這裡，他們應用數據驅動為依據的方法來幫助他們發展，
from statistical analysis, machine learning and
包括統計分析，機器學習和
text mining, to information visualization.
文字挖掘到資訊可視化。
And this need for data driven intelligence and skills is growing in companies and
而數據驅動的情報和技能的需求，
organizations throughout the world.
在全球的公司和組織中正在增長。
Let's start with a look at the roots of the field of data science.
我們來看看數據科學領域的根源。
The techniques and methodologies of data science stem from the fields of computer
數據科學的技術和方法起源於計算機科學
science and statistics.
與統計學領域。
One of the most well cited diagrams describing the field comes from Drew Conway
描述該領域，最常被人引用的圖表之一是從德魯•康威（Drew Conway），
where he suggested data science is the intersection of hacking skills,
他提議數據科學是駭客技能，
math and stats knowledge, and substantial expertise.
數學和統計知識的交集，以及豐富的專業知識。
This diagram might be a bit of an oversimplification, but
這個圖可能有點過分簡單，
I think it's a great start.
但我認為這是一個很好的開始。
Data science is definitely one of those areas where you ask ten people and
數據科學肯定是你問十個人
get ten different answers.
並得到十個不同答案的領域之一。
One thing that I think is missing from this diagram is the underlining need for
我認為圖中缺少的一件事是對
the scientific inquiry.
科學探究的強調。
You don't necessarily get this for having good hacking skills or math and
你不一定有這樣的科學探究，即使你有很好的駭客技能或數學和
statistic knowledge.
統計知識。
A good data scientist bring skepticism, experimentation,
一個好的數據科學家用懷疑，實驗，
simulation, and replication to bear on understanding a given phenomena.
模擬和複製來理解一個給定的現象。
Whether it be trying to predict sales at the coffee shop, cluster products in
無論是試圖去預測咖啡店的銷售量，分類集群產品
an online store, determine who's likely to win in election or
在網上商店中，確定誰可能在選舉中獲勝，或者
mine health data from physiological sensors like Fitbits.
從生理傳感器（如Fitbits）獲取健康數據。
In this specialization we're going to touch on all of these issue broadly but
在這個專業化課程中，我們將廣泛地關注所有這些問題，但是
really focus on skills.
真正關注在技巧方面。
In addition to the hacking skills Conway mentions,
除了康威提到的駭客技能之外，
we're going to develop some communication skills in the form of charting,
我們將開發一些溝通技巧，以圖表，
graphing, and related visualizations.
圖形和相關可視化的形式。
A good data scientist is one who can communicate their findings clearly to
一個好的數據科學家是一個可以將他們的發現清楚地傳達
others and having some fundamental tools in the toolkit as useful here.
給他人，並且在工具箱中有一些有用的基本工具。
We can find a more comprehensive and academic discussion in the work of
我們可以找到更全面和學術性的討論，
David Donoho, Professor of Statistics in Stanford.
從斯坦福大學統計教授David Donoho的著作裏。
Who's providing excellent commentary of views of the field in
他在一篇題為'50年的數據科學'的論文中，提出了
a paper entitled 50 years of data science.
對該領域的觀點和出色評論。
We've provided a link to that in a course resources.
我們在課程資源中提供了一個網路鏈接。
There's lots to think about with this paper,
這篇文章有很多的想法，
but I want to draw your attention to section 8,
但我想提請你注意第8節，
where he describes the field broadly as being made up of six activities.
他將這個領域廣泛地描述為由六個活動組成。
The first of these is Data Exploration and
第一個是數據探索和
Preparation, this involves cleaning data and manipulating it for further analysis.
準備，這涉及到清理數據和操縱數據以便進一步分析。
The second is Data Representation and Transformation.
第二個是數據表現和轉換。
This specialization is going to look at several different forms of
這個專業化課程將會查看幾種數據表現
representing data.
的不同形式。
Tabular structures in the first course, text data in the fourth course, and
第一個課程中的表格結構，第四個課程中的文字數據和
graph-based data in the last course.
最後課程中，基於圖形的數據。
These are just some of the kinds of data you have to deal with as a data scientist.
這些只是您作為數據科學家必需要處理的一些數據資料。
The third activity is Computing with Data, and Donoho mentioned specifically
第三個活動是使用數據計算，而Donoho具體提到了
the languages of R and Python as being fundamental here.
R和Python的語言程式在這裡是至關重要的。
He goes further and he talks about pipelining and
他進一步介紹了流水線法，
how data scientist need to be able to work with different languages for
數據科學家需要能夠使用不同的語言程式，
different parts on an analysis project and I think this is very true.
在分析項目中的不同的部分，我認為這是非常真實的。
Unlike enterprise software projects, where you might use one language for
與企業軟件項目不同，你可以使用一種語言程式來實現
implementing all of the functionality you need.
所需的所有功能。
Modern data science projects can span many different languages and
現代數據科學項目可以跨越許多不同的語言程式和
computing paradigms.
計算範式。
Knowing when to use the right tool for the job is an important attribute.
知道何時使用合適的工具，來完成工作項目是一個重要的質能屬性。
The fourth activity is Data Modeling. I think data modeling is a big space but
第四個活動是數據建模。我認為數據建模是有一個很大的範圍，
Donoho speaks specifically about predictive modeling,
但是Donoho特別具體地說明了預測模型，
which we’ll talk about in the third MOOC in this specialization and
這個我們將在MOOC第三個專業化課程中討論，加上
generative modeling.
生成模型。
There's some fundamental differences here, and I think the increased interest in
這裡有一些基本的區別，我認為對預測建模的
predictive modeling is helping to fuel the current data science push.
興趣越來越大，有助於推動當前數據科學的進展。
In particular, the modern world, with massive data streams and
特別是現今世界，擁有大量的數據流和
significant computational power,
可觀的計算能力，
gives us opportunity to rapidly experiment with making predictions.
為我們提供了機會來快速的實驗預測。
Allowing us to innovate and evaluate new data science techniques.
允許我們來創新和評估新的數據科學技術。
The fifth activity is Data Visualization and Presentation.
第五個活動是數據可視化和演示表達。
Now the word visualization brings with it a number of connotations, such as charting
現在，'可視化'這個詞包括了許多內涵，如圖表
and graphing, as well as 3D visualizations and interactive environments.
和圖形，以及三維(3D)可視化和互動式環境。
In the second course we'll learn the basics of information visualization, but
在第二課程中，我們將學習信息可視化的基本知識，但
keep in mind that info viz is a whole field of its own.
請記得，資訊可視化本身有一個自己的領域。
Finally, Donoho suggests there's sort of a meta activity which he calls
最後，Donoho提議，類似於的，元數據活動，他稱之為
the science about data science.
關於數據科學的科學。
That is understanding what works and what doesn't in data science, and
那就是理解在數據科學裏，什麼是行得通，什麼是行不通，
building ways to leverage these discoveries.
而利用這些發現來建立可行的方法。
We see examples of this as new tools and
我們看到這樣的例子，例如新的計算工具和
paradigms of computing are invented to change the way data science works.
範例被發明，來改變數據科學的工作方式。
I think Donoho provides a really nice overview of the area of the data science.
我認為Donoho提供了一個非常好的數據科學領域的概述。
In his paper he also alludes to several investments,
在他的文章中，他還提到了幾項
research institutions are putting into the field.
研究機構正在投入這個領域的投資。
Including the University of California in Berkeley, New York University,
包括加州大學伯克利分校，紐約大學，
MIT and the University in Michigan, here,
麻省理工學院和密歇根大學這裡，
which just kicked off a $100 million data science initiative.
我們剛剛啟動了1億美元的數據科學計劃。
Data science is becoming a fundamental way of understanding the world around us.
數據科學正在成為理解我們周邊世界的根本途徑。
While many institutions, including my own,
雖然包括我自己在內的許多機構
are starting to offer data science masters degrees and certificate.
都開始提供數據科學碩士學位和認可證書。
I think it's important to think of data science as a sort of epistemology, or
我認為將數據科學視為一種認識論或
a way of knowing.
一種瞭解認知的方式是很重要的。
Data science thinking can be useful in a variety of disciplines and careers.
數據科學的思考在各種學科和職業中都是很有用的。
It is a way of approaching problems and critical thinking skills.
它是一種處理問題途徑和批判性思維能力的方法。
But this is a skills based course, so in the next lecture we're going to jump right
這是一個技能為基礎的課程，所以在接下來的講座中，我們將直接
in and start talking about the Python programming language.
進入並開始談論Python程式語言。